For more information: https://dsevero.com

INTERESTS

BIO & RESEARCH Broadly, my interests are information theory, generative modeling, and data compression. Current compression algorithms are not well suited to handle structured and high-dimensional data, such as images and graphs. I'm interested in building computationally efficient entropy coders that can be used with deep generative models. I have 5 years of industry experience applying machine learning to real-world problems, as well as open-source contributions to large projects such as Dask and NeuralCompression.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Electrical & Computer Engineering - Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

Started Fall 2020

- Undergraduate Exchange Program (1 year)

2013 - 2014

2010 - 2015

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Brazil

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering

First Class Honours, 99th percentile.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Facebook AI Research (FAIR)

New York, Summer 2021

Research Scientist Intern with Karen Ullrich

Vector Institute for AI

Toronto, 2020 - Current

Ph.D. Student Researcher with Alireza Makhzani

PUBLICATIONS

Reys, Arthur D., Danilo Silva, Daniel Severo, et al.: Predicting Multiple ICD-10 Codes from Brazilian-Portuguese Clinical Notes. Accepted at BRACIS 2020. arXiv: 2008.01515 [cs.CL].

Ruan*, Yangjun, Karen Ullrich*, Daniel Severo*, et al.: Improving Lossless Compression Rates via Monte Carlo Bits-Back Coding. Accepted as a Long Talk at ICML 2021. arXiv: 2102.11086 [cs.LG].

Severo, Daniel, Elad Domanovitz, and Ashish Khisti: Regularized Classification-Aware Quantization. Accepted at BSC 2021. arXiv: 2107.09716 [cs.LG].

Severo*, Daniel, James Townsend*, Ashish Khisti, et al.: Your Dataset is a Multiset and You Should Compress it Like One. Accepted as a Talk in Deep Generative Models and Downstream Applications Workshop @ NeurIPS 2021. 2021.

PREPRINTS

Severo, Daniel, Flávio Amaro, Estevam R. Hruschka Jr, et al.: Ward2ICU: A Vital Signs Dataset of Inpatients from the General Ward. 2019. arXiv: 1910.00752 [cs.LG].

Severo*, Daniel, James Townsend*, Ashish Khisti, et al.: Compressing Multisets with Large Alphabets. 2021. arXiv: 2107.09202 [cs.IT].

AWARDS

Vector Scholarship in AI Recipient 2020-21

2020

The Vector Scholarship in AI supports the recruitment of top students to AI-related master's programs in Ontario and is valued at \$17,500.

https://vectorinstitute.ai/aimasters

NSERC Applied Research Rapid Response to COVID-19 Grant 2020 Our project titled "Canadian Hospital Simulator For Management of COVID19 Cases and Contact Tracing" was awarded \$75,000.00.

https://www.nserc-crsng.gc.ca/Innovate-Innover/CCI-COVID_eng.asp

Virtual Design Challenge Winner

2019

Won 1st place at the VDC hosted by The University of British Columbia with my paper *Proof of Novelty*. Received a cash prize of \$3,000.

https://github.com/dsevero/Proof-of-Novelty

Student Merit Award and Medal

2015

Graduated with the highest GPA ever obtained (at the time) for my major. Elected "Best Student" by the faculty of Electrical & Electronics Engineering at the Federal University of Santa Catarina.

Science Without Borders Scholarship

2013

Awarded a full scholarship that covered tuition, transportation, necessary materials and living costs to study 2 academic semesters at the University of Toronto.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Federal University of Santa Catarina - Teaching Assistant

Communications Theory
 Introduction to Electronics
 Single-Variable Calculus
 Fall and Winter 2013
 Fall 2010

CERTI Foundation - Programming Instructor

2010 - 2013

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Craystack

- https://github.com/j-towns/craystack/pulls?q=author:dsevero

Neural Compression

- https://github.com/facebookresearch/NeuralCompression

Dask & Dask-ML

- https://github.com/dask/dask/pulls?q=author:dsevero
- https://github.com/dask/dask-ml/pulls?q=author:dsevero

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

3778 Healthcare - Machine Learning Engineer	2018 - 2020
Linx Impulse - Head of Data Science	2016 - 2018
CERTI Foundation - Research Engineer	2015 - 2016
Wavetech Technology - Embedded Systems Intern	2015
CERTI Foundation - Electrical Engineering Intern	2010 - 2013
WEG Industries - Electrical Engineering Intern	Summers 2011 and 2012

REFERENCES

Prof. Ashish Khisti

University of Toronto

Professor and Canada Research Chair (Tier II)
Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering
https://www.comm.utoronto.ca/~akhisti/

Prof. Alireza Makhzani

Vector Institute

Faculty member at the Vector Institute for Artificial Intelligence Adjunct Professor and Canada CIFAR AI Chair Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering

http://www.alireza.ai/

Karen Ullrich, Ph.D.

Facebook AI Research (FAIR)

Research Scientist

https://karenullrich.info/

James Townsend, Ph.D.

University College London

https://j-towns.github.io/

Prof. Frank R. Kschischang

University of Toronto

Distinguished Professor of Digital Communication

Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering https://www.comm.utoronto.ca/frank/